Yumi's Cells 2
유미의 세포들 2
Episode 39: Laptop
39화: 노트북
First place* is mine! Mine! (First to leave a comment.)
1위*는 내꺼야! 내 거! (먼저 댓글을 남겨주세요.)
Oh yeah! First place! First place!
아 그래! 첫 번째 장소! 첫 번째 장소!
Its unique sweetness disappeared. It's boring!
특유의 단맛이 사라졌어요. 지루해요!
Writer Kim Yumi, are you going through a hard time? This is like a funeral march dragging on.
김유미 작가님, 힘든 시간 보내고 계시나요? 이것은 마치 장례 행진이 계속되는 것과 같습니다.
Why did you make a sequel? Just end it if you don't have anything to say.
왜 속편을 만들었나요? 할말 없으면 그냥 끝내세요.
I can't read this anymore. I'm leaving now.
나는 이것을 더 이상 읽을 수 없습니다. 나는 지금 떠난다.
What?
무엇?
Oh yeah! First place! Its unique sweetness has disappeared.
아 그래! 첫 번째 장소! 특유의 단맛이 사라졌어요.
The top comments are all malicious comments.
상위댓글은 모두 악성댓글입니다.
It's because it's so popular. There are no malicious comments if it's not popular.
워낙 인기가 많기 때문이죠. 인기가 없으면 악성 댓글은 없습니다.
But still, there are too many malicious comments these days.
그런데 요즘 악성댓글이 너무 많아요.
It's because the ending is almost near. They must be worried that it won't be a happy ending.
결말이 거의 가까워졌기 때문이다. 해피엔딩이 아닐까봐 걱정되겠죠.
Don't worry too much about it, Writer. You're going to give them a great ending.
너무 걱정하지 마세요, 작가님. 당신은 그들에게 멋진 결말을 선사할 것입니다.
A great ending?
훌륭한 결말?
Our company's employees are all looking forward to it, too.
우리 회사 직원들도 모두 기대하고 있어요.
Since you're not giving them any hints, they're all in suspense wondering what the ending will be.
아무런 힌트도 주지 않으니 결말이 어떻게 될지 다들 긴장하고 있습니다.
What will the ending be? I'm curious about that, too! Can't you let me know what the ending will be?!
결말은 어떻게 될까요? 나도 그것이 궁금하다! 결말이 어떻게 되는지 알려주실 수 없나요?!
Cook cell told me to bring this to you so you can gain some strength.
쿡셀이 힘 좀 얻으라고 이걸 가져오라고 하더군요.
Bye!
안녕!
A great ending! Goddess Yumi! Let's make the best ending!!
훌륭한 결말입니다! 유미 여신님! 최고의 엔딩을 만들어보자!!
Although you get the full support of everyone once you become the top priority, it's not necessarily a good thing.
일단 최우선 순위가 되면 모든 사람의 전폭적인 지지를 받게 되지만, 그것이 반드시 좋은 것은 아닙니다.
Oh, no. What should she do?
안 돼. 그녀는 어떻게 해야 합니까?
She has to end it well.
그녀는 그것을 잘 끝내야 한다.
What should she do if it doesn't go well?
일이 잘 안 되면 어떻게 해야 하나요?
- What if she gets cursed at more? - Stop it!
- 그 이상 욕을 먹으면 어쩌지? - 그만해요!
They said they're looking forward to a great ending.
멋진 결말이 기대된다고 하더군요.
If it's not a great ending, won't Yumi be ostracized?
좋은 결말이 아니면 유미는 배척당하지 않을까요?
I said stop it, please!
그만하라고 했어요, 제발!
The cell that is always attached to the top priority is Anxiety.
늘 최우선으로 붙어있는 세포는 불안이다.
If this doesn't go well, it's over! We used all of the down payment to buy the house.
이게 잘 안되면 끝이에요! 우리는 집을 구입하는 데 계약금을 모두 사용했습니다.
We took out a huge loan!
우리는 엄청난 대출을 받았습니다!
If things go badly, how will we pay back the loan?
상황이 나빠지면 어떻게 대출금을 갚을 수 있나요?
What will we do? What will we do? What will we do? What will we do?!
우리는 무엇을 할 것인가? 우리는 무엇을 할 것인가? 우리는 무엇을 할 것인가? 우리는 무엇을 할 것인가?!
I said stop it!
그만하라고 했어!
I'm so anxious that I can't write!
너무 불안해서 글을 쓸 수가 없어요!
You will send the manuscript tomorrow morning before coming to the wedding, right?
내일 아침 결혼식에 오기 전에 원고를 보내주실 거죠?
I will have to.
나는 그래야만 할 것이다.
Miss Writer, fighting! I'll see you at the ceremonial hall.
작가님, 화이팅! 예식장에서 뵙겠습니다.
Yes, fighting!
응, 파이팅!
Although Yumi was under a lot of stress ahead of the release of the sequel,
유미는 속편 개봉을 앞두고 스트레스를 많이 받았지만
the real incident occurred the night before Yi Da's wedding.
실제 사건은 이다의 결혼식 전날 밤에 일어났다.
Reason! Emergency, emergency!
이유! 비상, 비상!
- What is it? - I don't see the laptop!
- 그게 뭐죠? - 노트북이 보이지 않아요!
Carefully look for it. It must be somewhere.
조심스럽게 찾으십시오. 어딘가에 있을 거에요.
It's not there!
거기가 아니야!
It's not in the place where she usually charges it?
평소 충전하는 곳에 없나요?
Then what about the dining table?
그렇다면 식탁은 어떨까요?
What about under the bed?
침대 밑은 어떻습니까?
It's not there!
거기가 아니야!
Did she use a different bag?
그녀는 다른 가방을 사용했나요?
No!
아니요!
Did it get mixed in with the recyclables?
재활용품과 섞였나요?
I'm telling you it didn't!
그렇지 않았다고 말하고 있습니다!
It's not here. It's gone.
여기에는 없습니다. 사라졌습니다.
How much of the manuscript is in the laptop?
노트북 안에 원고가 얼마나 들어있나요?
Including the episode that I'm going to upload tomorrow, there are sixty pages for six chapters.
내일 올릴 회차까지 포함하면 총 6개 챕터에 60페이지가 됩니다.
That much? You didn't make a backup?
그 정도? 백업 안 하신 건가요?
I'm sure she left it somewhere when she went out.
나는 그녀가 외출할 때 그것을 어딘가에 두고 왔다고 확신합니다.
What places did she visit today?
오늘 그녀는 어떤 장소를 방문했나요?
It's because the ending is almost near. They must be worried that it won't be a happy ending.
결말이 거의 가까워졌기 때문이다. 해피엔딩이 아닐까봐 걱정되겠죠.
There! She had the laptop up until then.
거기! 그녀는 그때까지 노트북을 가지고 있었습니다.
Yes, Miss Writer?
네, 작가님?
- Your laptop? - Yes.
- 노트북요? - 예.
We were looking at my laptop together this morning and talking about the comments.
오늘 아침에 우리는 함께 노트북을 보며 댓글에 대해 이야기를 나누었습니다.
That was my laptop, though.
하지만 그것은 내 노트북이었습니다.
You didn't take your laptop out.
당신은 노트북을 꺼내지 않았습니다.
Did you lose it? What are you going to do?
잃어버렸나요? 당신은 무엇을 할 예정입니까?
Yes, well...
네, 글쎄요...
I have to find it. I'll probably find it.
나는 그것을 찾아야만 한다. 아마 찾을 거예요.
You backed it up, right? As long as the manuscript is all right ...
당신이 백업한 거죠, 그렇죠? 원고가 괜찮다면...
Oh, of course!
아, 물론이죠!
Goodbye.
안녕히 가세요.
She must have really lost it.
그녀는 정말 정신을 잃었나 봐요.
Let's not despair!
절망하지 말자!
For now, she can just go buy a new laptop tomorrow and rewrite it all!
지금으로서는 내일 새 노트북을 사서 전부 다시 작성하면 됩니다!
Rewrite it all? 60 pages?!
다 다시 쓰시겠어요? 60페이지?!
Don't you have the outline all in your head?
머릿속에 개요가 다 떠오르지 않나요?
In the end, Yumi couldn't find the laptop up to the morning of the wedding.
결국 유미는 결혼식 당일 아침까지 노트북을 찾지 못했다.
What will she do now? Everyone from the publishing company is going to the wedding.
이제 그녀는 무엇을 할 것인가? 출판사 사람들이 모두 결혼식에 갑니다.
What will she do? Come up with an excuse somehow!
그녀는 무엇을 할 것인가? 어떻게든 핑계를 대세요!
There's no manuscript to upload today,
오늘 업로드할 원고가 없어요
and there's no manuscript to upload next week either. Even if she writes, there are malicious comments.
그리고 다음 주에 업로드할 원고도 없습니다. 글을 써도 악성댓글이 있더라구요.
What do we do? They won't leave—
우리는 무엇을 합니까? 그들은 떠나지 않을 거야—
I don't want to be the prime cell.
나는 프라임 셀이되고 싶지 않습니다.
Take care.
잘 지내세요.
Don't look for me ever again!
다시는 나를 찾지 마세요!
Bye!
안녕!
Writer!
작가!
Writer abandoned her prime cell position and ran away.
작가는 프라임 셀 직위를 버리고 도망쳤다.
Thank you. Thank you.
감사합니다. 감사합니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Aigoo, Writer Yumi! You made it.
아이고, 유미 작가님! 당신이 해냈습니다.
Editor-in-Chief. Congratulations.
편집장. 축하해요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
- Where's Yi Da? - She's in the waiting room right now.
- 이다 씨는 어디 있어요? - 지금 대기실에 있어요.
You finished by the deadline before you came, right?
오기 전에 마감일까지 끝냈지?
- Yes. - I'll read it after the ceremony.
- 예. - 행사가 끝난 후에 읽겠습니다.
I'm looking forward to the last chapter.
마지막 장을 기대하고 있어요.
Yes.
예.
Oh, yes. Excuse me.
아, 그렇죠. 실례합니다.
- Congratulations. - Oh, thank you.
- 축하해요. - 아, 고마워요.
The groom's side
신랑쪽
Kim Yumi
김유미
Wow, Miss Yumi!
와, 유미 씨!
Oh, Bon Hui! Hello!
아, 본희! 안녕하세요!
- It's been a long time. It's been so long! - I know!
- 오랜만이에요. 너무 오랜만이에요! - 알아요!
It's good to see you.
만나서 반가워요.
Wait, I heard that you're the one who set up the bride and groom.
잠깐만요, 신랑 신부를 세우신 분은 당신이라고 들었습니다.
They said that the groom is your editor-in-chief.
신랑이 편집장이라고 하더라고요.
I didn't set them up.
나는 그것들을 설정하지 않았습니다.
Your order is ready.
주문이 준비되었습니다.
Really? He was a loser this time, too?
정말? 이번에도 패배자였나요?
Yeah. He was the worst of the worst.
응. 그는 최악 중의 최악이었습니다.
I'm not trying to find who is the worst!
나는 누가 최악인지 찾으려는 것이 아닙니다!
- I was really angry and— - Miss Writer.
- 정말 화가 났고— - 작가님.
Oh, Editor-in-Chief?
아, 편집장?
I saw you on my way to the publishing company.
출판사로 가는 길에 당신을 봤습니다.
Oh, I had plans with my friend here.
아, 친구랑 여기서 계획을 세웠어요.
I was actually going to leave soon.
사실은 곧 떠나려고 했어요.
Yi Da, say hello. This is my Editor-in-Chief. I've talked about him a lot, right?
이다야, 인사해. 제 편집장입니다. 내가 그 사람에 대해 많이 얘기했지, 그렇지?
This is my former co-worker, Yi Da.
이 사람은 나의 전 직장 동료인 이다입니다.
Hello, I'm Kang Yi Da.
안녕하세요 강이다입니다.
Hello. I'm Ahn Dae Yong.
안녕하세요. 저는 안대용입니다.
- You're the best! - Pardon?
- 당신이 최고예요! - 뭐라고요?
You're the one who chose Yumi's story.
유미의 이야기를 선택한 건 당신이에요.
I always told Yumi that you've got a great eye..
유미한테는 눈이 참 좋다는 말을 늘 했었는데..
You've really got a great eye for writers.
작가님 정말 눈썰미가 좋으시네요.
Well, that's because her writing is—
글쎄요, 그 이유는 그녀의 글이—
You're the best! Really the best!
당신은 최고입니다! 정말 최고!
What is this? Who is that cute creature?
이게 뭔가요? 저 귀여운 생명체는 누구일까요?
She said she's Kang Yi Da.
그녀는 자신이 강이다라고 말했습니다.
Let's save that. Kang Yi Da. [Kang Yi Da]
저장해두자. 강이다. [강이다]
Her name is Kang Yi Da.
그녀의 이름은 강이다입니다.
Cute Best (Jjang) Yi Da.
귀여운 베스트(짱) 이다.
The rhyme is perfect, too!
라임도 완벽해요!
- Hello! - Hello.
- 안녕하세요! - 안녕하세요.
Hello, I'm Ahn Dae Yong who greeted you last time. You remember me, right?
안녕하세요 지난번 인사드린 안대용 입니다. 나를 기억하지?
Oh, this ajeossi?
아, 이거 아저씨?
Yes, of course. Hello, how have you been?
물론이죠. 안녕하세요, 잘 지내셨나요?
I have a meeting nearby today.
오늘 근처에서 회의가 있어요.
If it's all right with you, would you like to have lunch together?
괜찮으시면 같이 점심 드실래요?
Julie Literature Editor-in-Chief Ahn Dae Yong
줄리문학 편집장 안대용
Yes, that sounds good.
네, 좋은 것 같아요.
What's with this ajeossi? It doesn't suit him to leave an emoticon.
이 아저씨는 뭐죠? 이모티콘을 남기는 것은 그에게 적합하지 않습니다.
He's cute.
그는 귀엽습니다.
I only introduced them to each other. I found out later that they were dating without me knowing.
서로 소개만 했어요. 나중에 알게 됐는데, 나도 모르게 둘이 데이트를 하고 있었던 거다.
What's with that? Oh, you also set Ruby up with her boyfriend.
그게 뭐야? 아, 루비가 남자친구랑 사귀게 놔두셨군요.
I also only introduced Ruby to him, and they started dating on their own.
저도 루비만 소개시켜줬고, 둘이서 둘이서 연애를 시작했어요.
Then I should stick by you from now on if I want to get married.
그럼 앞으로 결혼하고 싶으면 당신 옆에 있어야겠어요.
Oh right! We're catching up and forgot we haven't even given our congratulatory money yet. Just a moment!
아 맞다! 연락을 하고 있는데 아직 축의금도 안 드린 걸 깜빡했네요. 잠시만요!
I'm in charge of giving them the envelopes from the marketing team.
나는 마케팅팀에서 그들에게 봉투를 전달하는 일을 담당하고 있습니다.
Yu Ba Bi
유바비
Team Leader Yu couldn't come, so he put me in charge of it.
유 팀장님이 못 오셔서 저한테 맡겼어요.
I see.
알겠어요.
Do you know that he's going to an overseas branch?
그 사람이 해외 지사로 가는 거 알아요?
- An overseas branch? - Yes, he was assigned to Singapore.
- 해외 지사요? - 네, 싱가포르에 배정됐어요.
He said he couldn't come because he's leaving today. So he asked me to bring the envelopes.
오늘 떠나기 때문에 올 수 없다고 하더군요. 그래서 그는 나에게 봉투를 가져오라고 했습니다.
What's this? This is ridiculous.
이건 뭐죠? 이건 말도 안 돼요.
Writer cell ran away, and Love isn't here.
작가 세포는 도망갔고, 사랑은 여기에 없어요.
Are there cell villages that don't have a prime cell?
프라임 셀이 없는 셀 마을도 있나요?
- Reason. - Huh?
- 이유. - 뭐?
Is our Yumi really doing well right now?
우리 유미는 지금 정말 잘 지내고 있나요?
She broke off the wedding, and she failed to meet the deadline.
그녀는 결혼식을 중단했고 마감일을 지키지 못했습니다.
Hey, you can't be like that. Today is Yi Da's wedding. Let's not ruin the mood.
이봐요, 당신은 그렇게 될 수 없습니다. 오늘은 이다의 결혼식이다. 분위기 망치지 맙시다.
I'm saying that I'm sad. Everyone else gets married so easily.
나는 슬프다고 말하고 있다. 남들은 다 결혼을 너무 쉽게 해요.
- Is there anything else? - No, that's everything.
- 다른 건 없나요? - 아니, 그게 다야.
I just left. I'll call you when I get to the airport.
방금 떠났어요. 공항에 도착하면 전화할게요.
All right.
괜찮은.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
- Hello, this is the café at the Baekseok-dong intersection. - Oh, yes.
- 안녕하세요 백석동사거리 카페입니다. - 아, 그렇죠.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm calling the number that was left on the coupon.
쿠폰에 남겨둔 번호로 전화를 할게요.
I see. What is this about?
알겠어요. 이것은 무엇에 관한 것입니까?
She's a writer. I thought she would be looking for it.
그녀는 작가입니다. 나는 그녀가 그것을 찾고 있을 것이라고 생각했습니다.
Yes, that's right. She would be looking for it.
네, 맞습니다. 그녀는 그것을 찾고 있을 것입니다.
I'm glad that I had your phone number.
당신의 전화번호를 알게 되어 기뻐요.
Yes, thank you.
네, 감사합니다.
She's probably at the wedding right now.
그 사람은 아마 지금 결혼식장에 있을 거예요.
Should we head to the airport now?
이제 공항으로 가볼까요?
Oh, yes.
아, 그렇죠.
No! One moment. I've got to stop somewhere.
아니요! 잠시만요. 어딘가에 멈춰야 해요.
This is my first request.
이것이 나의 첫 번째 요청입니다.
More than anything else, please be considerate of each other.
무엇보다 서로 배려해 주시기 바랍니다.
Passionately taking in each other's charms and strengths
서로의 매력과 장점을 열정적으로 흡수하는 중
will make you happy ...
당신을 행복하게 해줄 거예요 ...
Are they going to give us steak?
스테이크를 주실 건가요?
- Or galbitang? - Be quiet.
- 아니면 갈비탕? - 조용히 하세요.
I want to eat steak.
스테이크를 먹고 싶어요.
- Oppa. - Hm?
- 오빠. - 흠?
By the way, isn't that woman in the pink dress pretty? The one on the bride's side?
그런데 저 핑크색 드레스 입은 여자 예쁘지 않나요? 신부 쪽이요?
- You're way prettier, Ruby. - What are you saying? That's obvious.
- 당신이 훨씬 더 예뻐요, 루비. - 무슨 말이에요? 그건 분명합니다.
Did I say something too obvious?
내가 너무 뻔한 말을 했나?
Next, ...
다음은 ...
a married couple always ...
부부는 항상...
Let's listen attentively to the good message.
좋은 말씀을 잘 들어보겠습니다.
- Yes, sir. - When the husband loves his wife
- 네, 선생님. - 남편이 아내를 사랑할 때
and when the wife loves her husband, only then can a true family be established.
그리고 아내가 남편을 사랑해야 참된 가정이 이루어질 수 있는 것입니다.
All right, everyone. Listen up!
좋아요, 여러분. 잘 들어보세요!
Writer has run away.
작가가 도망쳤어요.
We are in a bind. There is no place to retreat to.
우리는 곤경에 빠졌습니다. 물러설 곳이 없습니다.
Yumi couldn't meet the deadline today, and she lost the manuscript for the next three weeks.
유미는 오늘 마감일을 맞추지 못했고 앞으로 3주 동안 원고를 잃어버렸습니다.
As far as the ending goes, she doesn't even have any ideas.
결말에 관한 한 그녀는 아무런 아이디어도 갖고 있지 않습니다.
- Oh, no. - What should she do?
- 안 돼. - 그녀는 어떻게 해야 할까요?
All that she has left is a missed deadline, malicious comments,
그에게 남은 건 기한을 놓친 악플,
and the interest on her loan.
그리고 그녀의 대출금에 대한 이자를요.
So today's strategy...
그래서 오늘의 전략은...
is the 36th strategy! (From The Thirty-Six Strategems: "If all else fails, retreat.")
36번째 전략입니다! (36가지 전략에서: "다른 모든 방법이 실패하면 후퇴하세요.")
- Is that a strategy? - Thirty-sixth?
- 그게 전략인가요? - 36번째요?
As soon as the ceremony ends, Yumi will leave the ceremony hall,
예식이 끝나자마자 유미는 예식장을 떠날 예정이고,
turn her phone off, and go to Mom's house. - What?
전화기를 끄고 엄마 집으로 가세요. - 무엇?
And then she'll disappear!
그리고 그녀는 사라질 것이다!
Until when? Until Writer comes back and she comes up with a plan!
언제까지? 작가가 돌아와서 계획을 세울 때까지!
That's the only way that Writer Kim Yumi will survive today!
그것이 김유미 작가가 오늘도 살아남을 수 있는 유일한 길이다!
What makes love complete isn't passion ...
사랑을 완성시키는 것은 열정이 아니다...
Oh, wait! It's Ba Bi. It's Ba Bi! [New message from Yu Ba Bi]
아, 잠깐! 바비입니다. 바비에요! [유바비의 새 메시지]
Happiness is ...
행복은 ...
Yumi. How are you?
유미. 어떻게 지내세요?
You're probably at the wedding right now.
당신은 아마 지금 결혼식에 참석하고 있을 겁니다.
I got a call saying that you left your laptop at the café.
노트북을 카페에 두고 왔다고 연락이 왔어요.
I went to get it so I could bring it to you at the wedding,
결혼식 때 가져다 주려고 사러 갔어요
but I don't think I can make it because there is traffic.
하지만 교통 체증 때문에 갈 수 없을 것 같아요.
What time did you say your flight was?
비행기 시간이 몇시라고 하던가요?
I'm actually leaving for Singapore today.
사실 저는 오늘 싱가포르로 떠납니다.
♫ Did you doze off last night again? ♫
♫ 어젯밤에 또 졸았나요? ♫
♫ Are you standing at the end of your path? ♫
♫ 당신은 길의 끝에 서 있나요? ♫
♫ Close your eyes and come into my arms ♫
♫ 눈을 감고 내 품에 안겨 ♫
♫ Everything is all right ♫
♫ 모든 것이 괜찮습니다 ♫
♫ I can't even express it in words ♫
♫ 말로 표현조차 못해요 ♫
So, I'm sorry, Yumi,
그럼 미안해요, 유미 님,
but I left your laptop in the airport locker.
그런데 네 노트북을 공항 사물함에 두고 왔어.
I was trying to help you, but I'm afraid I ended up inconveniencing you. I'm sorry.
나는 당신을 도우려고 노력했지만 결국 당신을 불편하게 만들까봐 두렵습니다. 죄송합니다.
♫ One day I'll hold you tightly in my arms ♫
♫ 언젠가는 당신을 내 품에 꼭 안을 거예요 ♫
You know that I'm always rooting for Writer Kim Yumi, right?
제가 항상 김유미 작가님을 응원하고 있는거 아시죠?
Even if we've broken up, that won't change.
우리가 헤어져도 그건 변하지 않을 거예요.
I hope you write good stories. Take care.
좋은 이야기를 써주시길 바랍니다. 잘 지내세요.
♫ I will become the moon just for you ♫
♫ 당신만을 위한 달이 될게요 ♫
♫ So that you can breathe within me ♫
♫ 네가 내 안에서 숨 쉴 수 있도록 ♫
♫ Darkness and loneliness entirely ♫
♫ 완전히 어둠과 외로움 ♫
♫ will cease to exist ♫
♫ 더 이상 존재하지 않을 것이다 ♫
♫ 'Cause you're my star ♫
♫ 넌 나의 스타이니까 ♫
♫ No matter what kind of night falls, I will shine on you ♫
♫ 어떤 종류의 밤이 오더라도 나는 당신을 빛나게 할 것입니다 ♫
♫ so that you can fall asleep in the warmth of the moonlight ♫
♫ 달빛의 따뜻함 속에서 잠들 수 있도록 ♫
♫ 'Cause you are my star ♫
♫ 넌 나의 별이니까 ♫
♫ 'Cause you are my life ♫
♫ 당신은 내 인생이니까 ♫
♫ I'm just shining on your night ♫
♫ 난 그저 너의 밤을 빛낼 뿐이야 ♫
♫ When I met you like a miracle ♫
♫ 기적처럼 널 만났을 때 ♫
♫ I got to know love ♫
♫ 사랑을 알게 됐어요 ♫
♫ When you cry, everything ends for me ♫ So beautiful!
♫ 당신이 울면 모든 것이 끝나요 ♫ 너무 아름다워요!
♫ I'll give you all my light ♫
♫ 내 모든 빛을 너에게 줄게 ♫
♫ I will become the moon just for you ♫
♫ 당신만을 위한 달이 될게요 ♫
♫ So that you can breathe within me ♫
♫ 네가 내 안에서 숨 쉴 수 있도록 ♫
♫ Darkness and loneliness entirely ♫
♫ 완전히 어둠과 외로움 ♫
♫ will cease to exist ♫
♫ 더 이상 존재하지 않을 것이다 ♫
♫ 'Cause you're my star ♫
♫ 넌 나의 스타이니까 ♫
Yumi!
유미!
- Oh, Wung! - My meeting ended late. The ceremony isn't over, right?
- 오, 웡! - 회의가 늦게 끝났어요. 행사는 끝나지 않았죠?
The ceremony is over. Everyone's eating. Go on and head inside.
행사가 끝났습니다. 모두가 먹고 있어요. 계속해서 안으로 들어가세요.
Where are you going?
어디 가세요?
I need to go find something.
뭔가를 찾으러 가야 해요.
- What? - My laptop. I lost my laptop. Today's my deadline.
- 무엇? - 내 노트북. 노트북을 잃어버렸어요. 오늘이 내 마감기한이야.
- See you later. - Yumi. Yumi!
- 나중에 봐요. - 유미. 유미!
♫ 'Cause you are my life ♫
♫ 당신은 내 인생이니까 ♫
♫ I'm just shining on your night ♫
♫ 난 그저 너의 밤을 빛낼 뿐이야 ♫
You can take my car ...
내 차를 가져가세요...
Terminal 1
제1터미널
♫ I'm just shining on your night ♫
♫ 난 그저 너의 밤을 빛낼 뿐이야 ♫
It's locker number 14. You know the passcode, right?
14번 사물함이에요. 비밀번호는 아시죠?
Will you end your locker usage and remove your items? Yes. No.
사물함 사용을 종료하고 물건을 제거하시겠습니까? 예. 아니요.
Please wait a moment
잠시만 기다려주세요
Just a moment, please.
잠시만 기다려 주세요.
Thank you for your use. Please close the door completely after removing your items.
이용해주셔서 감사합니다. 물건을 꺼낸 후 문을 완전히 닫아주세요.
Too much time has gone by. I'm sure he's on the plane.
시간이 너무 많이 흘렀습니다. 나는 그가 비행기에 있다고 확신합니다.
Let's at least leave him a text message so he can see it when he gets there.
최소한 그 사람이 도착했을 때 볼 수 있도록 문자 메시지라도 남겨두자.
Departures
출발
I found my laptop. Things must have been hectic and busy.
노트북을 찾았어요. 일이 바쁘고 바빠졌을 것입니다.
Thank you for going out of your way.
먼 길을 떠나주셔서 감사합니다.
Huindol Village Bus Stop
흰돌마을 버스정류장
Ba Bi.
바비.
I...
나는...
have been ...
...
thinking about it a lot all this time.
그동안 생각을 많이 했어요.
I think I know what you're going to say.
무슨 말을 하려는지 알 것 같아요.
I had a feeling.
느낌이 들었습니다.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
By the time you see this, you'll be in Singapore, right?
이걸 볼 때쯤이면 이미 싱가포르에 계시겠죠?
I wish you all the best while you are there.
당신이 거기 있는 동안 최선을 다하길 바랍니다.
I'll also sincerely be rooting for you.
저도 진심으로 응원하겠습니다.
Oh? Message read
오? 메시지를 읽었습니다
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
Yumi.
유미.
Oh.
오.
I thought you'd be on the plane.
비행기 안에 있을 줄 알았는데.
It was delayed. There's heavy rain over there.
지연되었습니다. 거긴 비가 많이 오고 있어요.
I think it happened so I can see you before I go.
그런 일이 있었던 것 같아서 가기 전에 꼭 만나 볼 수 있도록 하려고요.
Really?
정말?
I'm glad that I got to see you and say goodbye before I left.
떠나기 전에 만나서 작별인사를 할 수 있어서 다행이에요.
You saved me.
당신이 나를 구했어요.
My entire manuscript was in here. Thank you.
내 원고 전체가 여기에 있었어. 감사합니다.
When will you finish the novel?
소설은 언제 끝낼 거예요?
The end of the year? If it goes well, around Christmas.
연말? 괜찮다면 크리스마스쯤.
Oh, I see.
알겠어요.
Finish it well.
잘 마무리하세요.
I want to, but I'm not skilled enough.
그러고 싶지만 실력이 부족해요.
You'll do well.
당신은 잘 할 것입니다.
What about a boyfriend?
남자친구는 어떡해요?
Did you get a boyfriend?
남자친구 생겼어?
- No. I don't have time to. - Really?
- 아뇨. 시간이 없어요. - 정말?
Whats this?
이게 뭐야?
Why is he smiling? What does that mean?
그 사람은 왜 웃고 있는 걸까요? 그게 무슨 뜻이에요?
Oh my goodness!
맙소사!
My heart is fluttering!
가슴이 두근두근!
Hey, hey! Are you guys starting up again?
이봐, 이봐! 여러분, 다시 시작하시나요?
Is this the first or second time? Knock it off!
이번이 처음인가요, 두 번째인가요? 그것을 노크하세요!
Ba Bi always speaks in a sweet manner.
바비는 항상 다정하게 말을 해요.
We know, we know.
우리는 알고 있습니다.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
- Me? - Do you have a girlfriend?
- 나? - 여자친구 있어요?
I am seeing someone.
나는 누군가를 만나고 있습니다.
- What's this? - See. You heard him, right?
- 이게 뭐죠? - 보다. 그 사람 말 들었죠?
- Get a hold of yourself. - I know. I said I know!
- 정신 좀 차려보세요. - 알아요. 나는 안다고 말했다!
Did I say anything?
내가 아무 말이라도 했나?
I see. I hope it goes well.
알겠어요. 나는 그것이 잘되기를 바랍니다.
Team Leader Ba Bi.
바비 팀장입니다.
We have to go in now.
이제 들어가야 해요.
Oh, really?
오, 진짜?
I'll head in.
들어가겠습니다.
Okay. Have a good trip.
좋아요. 좋은 여행 되세요.
Take care.
잘 지내세요.
By the way, was that woman from earlier your girlfriend?
그런데 아까 그 여자가 네 여자친구였어?
Oh, she's not.
아, 그렇지 않아요.
For some reason, I thought the vibe was ...
왠지 분위기가...
She's my ex-girlfriend.
그 사람은 내 전 여자친구예요.
What about now?
지금은 어떻습니까?
It's been a while since we broke up.
우리가 헤어진 지 꽤 됐어요.
Then why was she at the airport?
그러면 그녀는 왜 공항에 있었나요?
Things ended up that way coincidentally.
우연히 일이 그렇게 끝났습니다.
- It looked as if she was a girlfriend coming to see me off, right? - Yes.
- 꼭 나를 배웅하러 오는 여자친구 같았죠? - 예.
But, Team Leader, why won't you go on any blind dates?
그런데 팀장님, 소개팅은 왜 안 하시나요?
I've recommended several women, but you said you didn't want to meet any of them.
제가 여러 여자를 추천했는데 그 중 한 명도 만나고 싶지 않다고 하셨어요.
- Because I don't want to. - Why?
- 그러고 싶지 않으니까. - 왜?
Why are you smiling?
왜 웃고 있어요?
Why aren't you going on any dates?
왜 아무 데이트에도 안 가?
I'm not sure.
잘 모르겠습니다.
I don't really know why, either.
나도 왜 그런지 잘 모르겠어요.
Episode 40 The Return
40화 귀환
Love disappeared one year ago on Christmas Eve.
사랑은 1년 전 크리스마스 이브에 사라졌습니다.
♫ I didn't hear anything  ♫
♫ 아무 것도 듣지 못했어요 ♫
♫  The small light went out ♫
♫ 작은 불빛이 나갔다 ♫
Dating, damn you! This damned love affair!
데이트, 젠장! 이 빌어먹을 연애!
I'm telling you it's exasperating!
정말 짜증난다고 말씀드리고 싶어요!
The day that Love turned into the incarnation of rage
사랑이 분노의 화신으로 변한 날
Love. ♫ Ling Ling don't make a sad face ♫
사랑. ♫ Ling Ling 슬픈 표정 짓지 마세요 ♫
♫ Without my being vigilant in my heart there is no suspicious intent ♫
♫ 마음을 경계하지 않고는 의심의 여지가 없습니다 ♫
Give the prime cell position to Writer.
Writer에 프라임 셀 위치를 지정합니다.
♫ Ling Ling don't try to be understanding ♫
♫ Ling Ling 이해하려고 하지 마세요 ♫
♫ Aside from minor quirks I am usually such a person ♫
♫ 사소한 단점을 제외하면 나는 대개 그런 사람이다 ♫
and got kicked out of her position as the prime cell.
그리고 프라임 셀 자리에서 쫓겨났습니다.
Love, who was banished to another dimension,
다른 차원으로 추방된 사랑
didn't return even when Yumi ran into Wung as if it were fate,
유미는 운명처럼 웅과 마주쳐도 돌아오지 않았고,
or even when she got back together with Ba Bi.
아니면 바비와 다시 만났을 때도요.
Yumi, should we... ♫ I'll keep remembering the past. We're going to fall. ♫
Yumi, should we... ♫ 나는 과거를 계속 기억할 거예요. 우리는 넘어질 것입니다. ♫
get married? ♫ Even so it's better than being dizzy ♫
결혼해? ♫ 그래도 어지러운 것보다는 낫지 ♫
Let's get married. ♫ Ling Ling you're such a fool ♫
결혼하자. ♫ Ling Ling 당신은 정말 바보예요 ♫
Even when she was proposed to... ♫ There isn't anyone who loves you ♫
심지어 그녀에게 프러포즈를 받았을 때도... ♫ 당신을 사랑하는 사람은 아무도 없어요 ♫
I have been ♫ as much as I do ♫
나는 있었다 ♫ 나만큼 ♫
thinking about it a lot all this time. ♫ Ling Ling you'll know eventually ♫
그동안 생각을 많이 했어요. ♫ Ling Ling 당신은 결국 알게 될 거예요 ♫
I think I know what you're going to say. ♫ Ordinary things ♫
무슨 말을 하려는지 알 것 같아요. ♫ 평범한 일들 ♫
and even when they were breaking up, Love didn't come back. ♫ don't suit you at all ♫
그리고 헤어지는 순간에도 사랑은 돌아오지 않았습니다. ♫ 전혀 어울리지 않아 ♫
- I'm better at that. - Wait, why?
- 난 그게 더 나아요. - 잠깐, 왜요?
Of course, it's not like there was never a time when her heart fluttered after that.
물론 그 이후로 그녀의 마음이 설렌 적이 단 한 번도 없었던 것은 아니다.
Writer Yumi!
작가 유미!
Oppa!
오빠!
Mr. Yeon In*? (Also means one's love)
연인씨*요? (사랑을 의미하기도 함)
Oh, my friend said he wanted to greet you before he left. Say hello, Yeon In. This is Writer Yumi.
아, 친구가 떠나기 전에 인사드리고 싶다고 하더군요. 안녕하세요, 연인님. 작가 유미 입니다.
Hello.
안녕하세요.
I'm really enjoying My Love Muse.
마이 러브 뮤즈를 정말 재미있게 즐기고 있어요.
Thank you. ♫ Error! Error! ♫
감사합니다. ♫ 오류! 오류! ♫
- It's Love! Love is here! - She said Love is here!
- 사랑이에요! 사랑이 여기에 있습니다! - 사랑이 여기 있다고 하더군요!
So she's finally back!
그래서 그녀가 마침내 돌아왔습니다!
She sometimes wonders, "Is this possibly a romantic feeling?" But...
그녀는 가끔 '이게 로맨틱한 감정일까?'라고 궁금해한다. 하지만...
Me? I'm not Love, I'm Curiosity.
나? 나는 사랑이 아니라 호기심이다.
There are a lot of cases where it's not.
그렇지 않은 경우도 많습니다.
It's Curiosity. It's Curiousity!
큐리오시티입니다. 그것은 호기심입니다!
What's going on? Why is he acting like that?
무슨 일이야? 그 사람은 왜 그런 행동을 하는 걸까요?
- You guys were all fooled. - So annoying.
- 너희들은 모두 속았어. - 너무 짜증나.
Romance
로맨스
Ma'am,
부인,
here is the book you were looking for.
여기 당신이 찾고 있던 책이 있습니다.
- Thank you. - Wow, he's handsome.
- 감사합니다. - 와, 그 사람 정말 잘생겼어요.
It must be real this time!
이번에는 진짜일 것 같아요!
Love has really come back!
정말 사랑이 돌아왔습니다!
Handsome men are innocent.
잘생긴 남자는 순수해요.
Where's Love?
사랑은 어디에 있나요?
It's not her.
그녀가 아닙니다.
It's not her!
그녀가 아니야!
It was Sensitivity.
민감성이었습니다.
- What the heck? - I'm so annoyed.
- 대체 뭐야? - 정말 짜증나.
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
I think you dropped this.
내 생각엔 네가 이걸 떨어뜨린 것 같아.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Really, really, my heart just dropped.
정말 정말 심장이 쿵 떨어졌어요.
It is real this time. This time it's really Love!
이번에는 진짜입니다. 이번에는 정말 사랑입니다!
Guys, isn't that guy so sexy?
여러분, 저 사람 너무 섹시하지 않나요?
I want to touch his arms just once.
그의 팔을 한 번만 만져보고 싶다.
Get rid of him.
그를 제거하십시오.
At first, there were times we were fooled by her feelings,
처음에는 그녀의 감정에 속았던 적도 있었는데,
but now Yumi doesn't fall for it either.
하지만 이제 유미도 그것에 빠지지 않습니다.
Eonni. You were piercing a hole with your eyes at Oppa Z's friend.
언니. 당신은 오빠Z의 친구에게 눈으로 구멍을 뚫고 있었습니다.
Are you falling in love?
당신은 사랑에 빠지고 있습니까?
It's not like that. Go away.
그렇지 않습니다. 저리 가요.
- That's suspicious. - I told you it wasn't like that.
- 의심스럽네요. - 그런 건 아니라고 했잖아.
Okay.
좋아요.
Will Love return this Christmas?
이번 크리스마스에 사랑이 돌아올까요?
No.
아니요.
This Christmas, these guys returned.
이번 크리스마스에는 이 사람들이 돌아왔습니다.
Fat
지방
Fat cells.
지방 세포.
We have finally arrived on a new land.
우리는 마침내 새로운 땅에 도착했습니다.
This is where we will be living from now on.
이제부터 우리가 살 곳은 바로 이곳이다.
Leader!
지도자!
Then where do we settle down at?
그럼 우리는 어디에 정착할까요?
Let's go to Gaseum*! (Refers to the chest or heart.)
가숨*으로 가자! (가슴이나 심장을 말합니다.)
Gaseum! Gaseum! Gaseum! Gaseum 2 Yumi miles
가슴! 가슴! 가슴! 가지움 2유미 마일
No, let's go to Yeopguri*! (Refers to the waist)
아니 엽구리로 가자*! (허리를 나타냄)
Huh? Yeopguri 55 Yumi miles
뭐? 엽구리 55 유미마일
- Yeopguri? - Yeopguri is safe.
- 엽구리요? - 엽구리는 안전해요.
Once we settled on the waist, we are less likely to be kicked out.
일단 허리에 안착하면 쫓겨날 확률이 줄어듭니다.
On top of that, a lot of our Fat siblings already live there.
게다가 이미 우리 Fat 형제자매들도 많이 살고 있어요.
Let's go! Let's go!
갑시다! 갑시다!
Let's go!
갑시다!
To the paradise of happiness, Yeopguri!
행복의 천국 엽구리로!
Yeopguri!
엽구리!
- Yeopguri! - Woo!
- 엽구리! - 우!
No, it's not that way. Come here.
아니요, 그렇지 않습니다. 이리 오세요.
It's not?
그렇지 않습니까?
Seriously, why can't I figure this out?
진심으로, 나는 왜 이것을 알아낼 수 없습니까?
Yumi is currently suffering a deadline syndrome, pressured to finish her manuscript before the deadline.
유미는 현재 마감일 전에 원고를 완성해야 한다는 압박감으로 마감 증후군을 앓고 있습니다.
♫ I also wouldn't know ♫
♫ 나도 몰랐을 거야 ♫
♫ my heart ♫
♫ 내 마음 ♫
I just have to write five chapters.
다섯 장만 써야 해요.
Just five chapters.
5장만요.
♫ There's a me ♫
♫ 내가 있다 ♫
Why does it have to be five chapters?
왜 5장이어야 합니까?
♫ I don't know ♫
♫ 모르겠어요 ♫
♫ Even if I walk slowly ♫
♫ 천천히 걸어도 ♫
♫ My heart is running far away there ♫
♫ 내 마음은 그곳으로 멀리 달려가고 있어요 ♫
Why is it so messy?
왜 이렇게 지저분해?
Reason, how about we clean the room before we write?
이유, 글을 쓰기 전에 방을 청소하는 게 어때요?
Wait, are you crazy?!
잠깐, 미쳤어?!
Why are you doing things you don't normally do, on the day of her deadline?!
마감일에 왜 평소에 안 하던 짓을 하는 거죠?!
Reason, I suddenly really want to find out where the best vacation spots are
이유야, 갑자기 최고의 휴양지가 어디인지 너무 알고 싶어
that Hollywood celebs go.
할리우드 유명인들이 가는 곳이죠.
Let's try looking it up, huh?
한번 찾아보자, 응?
Curiosity, why are you acting like this too? ♫ Even if I walk carefully ♫
호기심아, 너도 왜 이러는 걸까? ♫ 조심스럽게 걸어도 ♫
♫ my heart is far away there ♫
♫ 내 마음은 저기 멀리 있어요 ♫
♫ Even at night when everyone is asleep ♫
♫ 모두가 잠든 밤에도 ♫
♫ It's racing wide awake ♫
♫ 잠에서 깨어나 질주하고 있어요 ♫
- When you get deadline syndrome, - It's nice.
- 마감증후군이 나타나면, - 좋네요.
everything except the deadline becomes interesting.
마감일을 제외한 모든 것이 흥미로워집니다.
Where is this?
여긴 어디야?
♫ There is a world I don't know ♫
♫ 내가 모르는 세계가 있다 ♫
♫ Even if I spend a day when nothing happens ♫
♫ 아무 일도 일어나지 않는 하루를 보내도 ♫
These hairs. ♫ My heart is heading somewhere ♫
이 머리카락. ♫ 내 마음은 어딘가로 향하고 있어요 ♫
♫ Even I still don't know ♫
♫ 나도 아직은 모르겠어 ♫
♫ It's running there far away ♫
♫ 저 멀리 저쪽으로 달려가고 있어요 ♫
♫ It shouldn't run so fast ♫
♫ 너무 빨리 달려서는 안 돼요 ♫
♫ Even if I knew I can't do anything with my heart ♫
♫ 마음으로는 아무것도 할 수 없다는 걸 알면서도 ♫
This is so fun!
정말 재미있어요!
It's been a while, should I wash the blankets, too?
오랜만인데 이불도 빨래할까?
That's enough!
그거면 충분해요!
I'm going crazy.
나는 미쳐 가고있다.
Why are the last five chapters so hard?
마지막 5장은 왜 이렇게 어려운 걸까요?
I'm even sleepy.
심지어 졸려요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Eonni, when are you done?
언니, 언제 끝나요?
I don't know. I don't have a plan.
모르겠습니다. 나는 계획이 없습니다.
I don't think I'm going to meet the deadline.
마감일을 지키지 못할 것 같아요.
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
We are all preparing a party and waiting for you!
우리는 모두 파티를 준비하고 당신을 기다리고 있습니다!
A party?
파티?
Everyone is waiting to congratulate you when you finish your manuscript.
당신이 원고를 완성하면 모두가 당신을 축하하기 위해 기다리고 있습니다.
In the middle of the day?
한낮에?
We're going to start now and go on all night.
우리는 지금 시작해서 밤새도록 계속할 것입니다.
Hurry up and come.
서둘러서 오세요.
Miss Writer, it's not a lie. The microbrew here is amazing. Hurry over!
작가님, 거짓말이 아닙니다. 여기의 양조장은 훌륭합니다. 서둘러요!
Eonni Yi Da said she's coming too. Straight from her honeymoon trip.
언니이다도 온다고 하더군요. 신혼여행을 마치고 바로.
Are you going to sit alone in your room and write all night on Christmas Eve?
크리스마스 이브에 혼자 방에 앉아 밤새도록 글을 쓸 건가요?
Eonni, do you really want to live like that?
언니, 정말 그렇게 살고 싶나요?
No.
아니요.
So quickly finish and come here!
그러니까 빨리 끝내고 여기로 오세요!
A party?
파티?
That sounds good.
좋은 것 같네요.
What?
무엇?
I just thought of something.
방금 뭔가 생각이 났어요.
If I make the ending happen at a year-end party...
송년회에서 엔딩을 보게 된다면...
Eonni, I can't hear you very well.
언니, 잘 안 들려요.
Ah, that's right! That's it!
아, 그렇구나! 그게 다야!
That's where they meet for the first time.
그곳이 그들이 처음으로 만나는 곳이다.
Coincidentally, at the year-end party.
우연히 송년회에서.
The music is so loud that they can't even exchange names.
음악이 너무 커서 이름을 교환할 수도 없습니다.
What? What did you just say?
무엇? 방금 뭐라고 했어?
Okay, I'm hanging up!
알았어, 끊을게!
That's right. ♫ Are you paying attention to me? ♫
좋아요. ♫ 나에게 관심을 기울이고 있나요? ♫
This is how it can go. ♫  Or is it meaningless? ♫
이렇게 갈 수 있습니다. ♫ 아니면 의미가 없나요? ♫
♫ Do our eyes keep meeting? ♫
♫ 우리 눈이 계속 마주치나요? ♫
♫ Or were you just looking at something behind me? ♫
♫ 아니면 내 뒤에 있는 뭔가를 보고 있었나요? ♫
That day was Christmas Eve.
그날은 크리스마스 이브였습니다.
Yeon Jae, who is going to the year-end party thrown by her company,
회사에서 주최하는 송년회에 가는 연재
ends up meeting him as if it's fated. ♫ I'm going to continue to hide it ♫
운명처럼 그를 만나게 된다. ♫ 계속해서 숨길 예정이에요 ♫
♫ so you won't know how I feel ♫
♫ 내 기분이 어떤지 당신은 모를 거예요 ♫
But because the music is too loud,
하지만 음악이 너무 시끄러워서
she can't hear him when he tells her his name.
그가 자신의 이름을 말해도 그녀는 그의 말을 들을 수 없습니다.
♫ Am I the only one you're nice to? ♫
♫ 당신에게 친절한 사람은 나뿐인가요? ♫
But he remembered Yeon Jae's name. ♫ Am I the only one who thinks so? ♫
그런데 그는 연재의 이름을 기억하고 있었다. ♫ 나만 그렇게 생각하는 걸까? ♫
Like a miracle.
기적처럼.
When a writer's block suddenly clears, ♫ I really want to know how you feel ♫
작가의 블록이 갑자기 해소되면, ♫ 당신의 기분이 어떤지 정말 알고 싶어요 ♫
it's extremely thrilling. ♫ What is obvious ♫
매우 스릴이 넘칩니다. ♫ 무엇이 명백한가 ♫
Then it's immediately time for Endorphin. Endorphin
그렇다면 바로 엔돌핀이 필요한 때입니다. 엔돌핀
Everyone, we're here! ♫ Although there aren't enough clues ♫
여러분, 저희가 왔습니다! ♫ 단서가 충분하지 않지만 ♫
♫ I have my hunch that I care about you ♫
♫ 나는 당신에게 관심이 있다는 예감이 듭니다 ♫
Everybody shout together!
모두 함께 외쳐요!
Who are we?
우리는 누구입니까?
En-dor-phin!
엔도르핀!
"I remember." "What?"
"기억해요." "무엇?"
♫ Oh, I want to hear your heart ♫
♫ 아, 네 마음을 듣고 싶어 ♫
The End
끝
Enter
입력
The end.
끝.
Send
보내기
Your email has been sent successfully.
귀하의 이메일이 성공적으로 전송되었습니다.
I sent you the manuscript ^^
원고 보내드렸습니다^^
I'm done!
난 끝났어!
It's done!!!
다 됐다!!!
It's been a year since she became a writer. During that time, Yumi wrote two novels, My Love Muse
작가가 된 지 벌써 1년이 됐다. 그 동안 유미는 『나의 사랑 뮤즈』라는 두 권의 소설을 썼습니다
and its sequel.
그리고 그 속편.
It's so refreshing.
정말 상쾌해요.
Kim Yumi, you worked hard.
김유미 씨, 고생했어요.
- Good job, Yumi.
- 잘했어, 유미.
You worked hard, Yumi!
고생했어요 유미님!
Good job, Yumi.
잘했어, 유미.
The cell village is also busy at the end of the year.
세포마을은 연말에도 분주하다.
After the Endorphin concert, there's a year-end awards ceremony.
엔돌핀 콘서트가 끝나면 연말 시상식이 있어요.
It's a beautiful night.
아름다운 밤이에요.
Yumi Awards
유미상
All right, then. I'll announce this year's award winners.
그럼요. 올해의 수상자를 발표하겠습니다.
End of the year closing.
연말 결산.
This year's Best Cell Award selected by Yumi's cells goes to ...
유미의 세포가 선정한 올해 베스트 셀상은...
It can't be any other cell but me. It's embarrassing to pretend not to know.
나 외에는 다른 세포일 수 없습니다. 모르는 척 하는 게 부끄러워요.
The Best Cell Award!
베스트 셀상!
The winner is... The winner is...
승자는... 승자는...
We'll be back after the commercials.
광고 끝나고 다시 돌아오겠습니다.
What ...
뭐...
My Love Muse 2! Currently a best-seller! [Find it at Julie's Bookstore now!]
My Love Muse 2! 현재 베스트셀러! [지금 줄리서점에서 만나보세요!]
Yumi Awards Best Cell Award
유미상 최고의 세포상
Sensitivity - Writer - Flowy
감도 - 작가 - Flowy
The winner is ...
승자는 ...
Ba Bi's cells!
바비의 세포!
Yumi Awards- The Best Cell Award Ba Bi's cells
유미상-베스트셀상 바비의 세포
♫ Welcome to Ba Bi's world! Hola! ♫
♫ Ba Bi의 세계에 오신 것을 환영합니다! 안녕하세요! ♫
I can't believe this, seriously!
정말 믿을 수 없어요!
As Ba Bi's cells are currently living overseas,
바비의 세포들은 현재 해외에 거주하고 있어
they are unable to attend the award ceremony.
그들은 시상식에 참석할 수 없습니다.
- I will accept in their— - Hey!
- 나는 그들의— - 이봐!
I'm the one who made Yumi a writer!
유미를 작가로 만든 건 바로 나!
And I made the first and second books a success!
그리고 첫 번째와 두 번째 책을 성공적으로 만들었어요!
Naturally, you should be giving that award to me!
당연히 그 상은 나한테 줘야지!
What kind of bulls**t is this award ceremony!
이번 시상식은 무슨 개소리야!
Let me go!
날 보내줘!
Writer, calm down.
작가님, 진정하세요.
You are the one who wrote the books, but Ba Bi was the one who saved you.
책을 쓴 사람은 당신이지만 당신을 구한 사람은 바비였습니다.
What? Ba Bi saved me?
무엇? 바비가 나를 구했다고?
So I'm wondering, can you write something for me? ♫ Let's build a little house ♫
그래서 궁금해요. 저를 위해 뭔가 써주실 수 있나요? ♫ 작은 집을 짓자 ♫
I think you would do well, Assistant Manager Yumi. ♫ in front of the river ♫
유미 대리님, 잘하실 것 같아요. ♫ 강 앞에서 ♫
The first one to recognize our talent was Ba Bi. ♫ Let's raise our dreams ♫
우리의 재능을 가장 먼저 알아본 사람은 바비였다. ♫ 꿈을 키우자 ♫
The one who always supported us was also Ba Bi. ♫ over the mountain peak there ♫
늘 우리를 응원해준 사람도 바비였다. ♫ 저기 산봉우리 너머로 ♫
♫ My dear, ♫
♫ 내 사랑, ♫
The one who even found our laptop in the end was Ba Bi, too.
결국 우리 노트북을 찾아낸 사람도 바비였다.
Writer Cell
작가 셀
If Ba Bi hadn't believed in you, you probably would have already been buried here. ♫ Let's hide in our little house and kiss ♫
바비가 당신을 믿지 않았다면 당신은 이미 여기에 묻혔을 겁니다. ♫ 우리 작은 집에 숨어 키스하자 ♫
Do you admit it? ♫ I will build a fortress in your heart ♫
인정하시나요? ♫ 나는 당신의 마음에 요새를 세울 것입니다 ♫
I admit it. ♫ when you have nowhere to go ♫
나는 그것을 인정한다. ♫ 갈 곳이 없을 때 ♫
♫ I will take it to you ♫
♫ 내가 가져갈게 ♫
♫ and open your door ♫
♫ 그리고 문을 열어라 ♫
Thanks to you, I was able to finish my manuscript smoothly.
덕분에 원고를 원활하게 마칠 수 있었습니다.
Thank you. ♫ If time were to move backwards ♫
감사합니다. ♫ 시간이 거꾸로 간다면 ♫
Merry Christmas.
메리 크리스마스.
♫ I won't let you go ♫
♫ 난 당신을 보내지 않을 거예요 ♫
♫ Both the next time and  ♫
♫ 다음번에도 ♫
♫ the day after tomorrow, we ♫
♫ 내일 모레, 우리는 ♫
Notebook Recipient: Kim Yumi
노트북 수신자 : 김유미
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Once she finished the book, there was something she had to do first.
책을 다 읽고 나면, 그녀가 먼저 해야 할 일이 있었습니다.
What is this?
이게 뭔가요?
[Laptop]
[노트북]
Hello.
안녕하세요.
Wung. Why did you send a laptop?
웅. 노트북은 왜 보내셨나요?
Oh! It arrived?
오! 도착했나요?
You said you lost yours. I thought you would need one right away.
당신은 당신의 것을 잃었다고 말했습니다. 나는 당신에게 당장 하나가 필요할 것이라고 생각했습니다.
You're not tech savvy.
당신은 기술에 정통하지 않습니다.
Wait ... Wung, I'm grateful, but I found my laptop.
잠깐... 웅, 고마워요. 그런데 노트북을 찾았어요.
Oh, really? That's great.
오, 진짜? 훌륭해요.
So I will send this back to you.
그래서 이것을 당신에게 다시 보내 드리겠습니다.
That's okay. Just use it.
괜찮습니다. 그냥 사용하세요.
It has the best performance because it's the latest model.
최신모델이라 성능이 가장 좋습니다.
No, I can't. Why would you buy me a laptop?
아니요, 그럴 수 없습니다. 왜 나에게 노트북을 사주려고 합니까?
Why? It could just be a gift from a fan.
왜? 그냥 팬이 준 선물일 수도 있어요.
So you can write good stories.
그래야 좋은 글을 쓸 수 있습니다.
No, this is really not right. I will send it back to you.
아니요, 이건 정말 옳지 않습니다. 다시 보내드리겠습니다.
If you send it back then I will send it back to you again.
다시 보내주시면 다시 보내드리겠습니다.
What?
무엇?
And if you send it again then I will it back to you again and again.
그리고 다시 보내주시면 계속해서 다시 보내드리겠습니다.
Come on, what kind of stubbornness is that?
자, 그게 무슨 고집이냐?
I have a call coming in.
전화가 걸려와요.
Talk to you later.
나중에 얘기하세요.
Hello? Wung?
안녕하세요? 웅?
So she went to return it personally.
그래서 그녀는 그것을 개인적으로 돌려주러 갔다.
Oh! Miss Yumi!
오! 유미씨!
Aren't you Miss Yumi?
유미 씨 아닌가요?
Mr. Louis, it's been a long time.
루이스 씨, 오랜만이에요.
It's certainly been a long time.
확실히 오랜 시간이 걸렸습니다.
What brings you here?
무슨 일로 여기까지 왔나요?
Come in.
들어오세요.
I can wait in the lobby, though.
하지만 로비에서 기다릴 수 있어요.
What are you saying?
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
If ever I let you wait in the lobby
로비에서 기다리게 했다면
then Wung, that punk
그럼 Wung, 그 새끼
no, I mean CEO Gu would kill me.
아니, 구 대표가 나를 죽일 것이라는 뜻이다.
It's about time for the meeting to be over, so wait for a moment.
이제 회의가 끝날 시간이니까 잠시만 기다려주세요.
Sure.
확신하는.
Please be comfortable.
편안하게 지내시기 바랍니다.
Sorry ... can I ask for your autograph later?
죄송해요... 나중에 사인 부탁드려도 될까요?
Autograph?
자필?
Yes. My girlfriend is a fan of "My Love Muse."
예. 제 여자친구는 '마이 러브 뮤즈'의 팬이에요.
Yes.
예.
Then I will be back for your autograph later.
그럼 나중에 사인 받으러 다시 오겠습니다.
- Please be comfortable. - All right.
- 편안하게 지내세요. - 괜찮은.
I'm impressed.
나는 감동했다.
Gu Wung has really succeeded.
Gu Wung은 정말 성공했습니다.
KU WOONG GAMES CEO Gu Wung.
구웅게임즈 대표 구웅.
Wait. I think I have seen this name a lot somewhere.
기다리다. 이 이름은 어디서 많이 본 것 같아요.
Storm Man. UlaUla.
스톰맨. 울라울라.
My Ssarang Muse.
나의 싸랑 뮤즈.
Walwal* (To be quick.)
월왈* (빠르게.)
It's so interesting! The most interesting in the world!
정말 흥미롭습니다! 세상에서 가장 흥미로운 것!
I can't wait for Monday!
월요일이 너무 기다려진다!
The writer is a genius at the very least.
작가는 적어도 천재이다.
She's messing with the readers! Amazing!
그녀는 독자들을 엉망으로 만들고 있습니다! 놀라운!
- Kim Yumi is the best! - Julie Publishing, give the writer a big payment for the manuscript!
- 김유미 최고! - 줄리출판사, 작가에게 원고료를 거액으로 지급하라!
My Love Muse is the best!
내 사랑 뮤즈가 최고예요!
Writer Kim Yumi is the best!
김유미 작가님 최고!
That's right.
좋아요.
The usernames that kept on posting compliments every morning.
아침마다 계속 칭찬글을 올려주시는 닉네임들.
All this time, Wung was the one who posted those?
그동안 그 글을 게시한 사람이 Wung이었나요?
♫ Even if I don't extend my hand the feeling of warmth ♫
♫ 손을 뻗지 않아도 따뜻한 느낌 ♫
Every day for a year, without missing one day?
1년 동안 하루도 빠짐없이 매일?
How could this be? I got so much strength from all those comments.
어떻게 이런 일이 일어날 수 있습니까? 그 댓글들에 많은 힘을 얻었습니다.
This is really so like Gu Wung. ♫ comes and comforts me ♫
정말 구웅님과 너무 닮아있습니다. ♫ 와서 나를 위로해 주어요 ♫
Gu Wung! Gu Wung! Gu Wung! ♫ Like a star ♫
구웅! 구웅! 구웅! ♫ 별처럼 ♫
♫ Always be at my side ♫
♫ 항상 내 옆에 있어줘 ♫
Gu Wung! Gu Wung!
구웅! 구웅!
I have an emergent suggestion. ♫ Like a star shining in the dark night ♫
긴급 제안이 있습니다. ♫ 어두운 밤에 빛나는 별처럼 ♫
Let's make one more cell award for this year. ♫ always shine brightly by my side ♫
올해도 셀상을 하나 더 만들어보자. ♫ 언제나 내 곁에서 밝게 빛나줘 ♫
Wung's cells as a co-winner.
Wung의 세포가 공동 우승자입니다.
♫ Like a star ♫
♫ 별처럼 ♫
♫ while looking at me smile brightly ♫
♫ 나를 바라보며 밝게 웃어 ♫
♫ You who are so precious to me ♫
♫ 나에게 너무나 소중한 당신 ♫
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
♫ Always by my side ♫
♫ 언제나 내 곁에 ♫
♫ Remain by my side ♫
♫ 내 곁에 있어줘 ♫
Yumi!
유미!
Sir!
선생님!
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
잘 지내요. 잘 지내요.
Are you really okay?
정말 괜찮아요?
I'm perfectly fine, so you can leave, Gye Rim.
난 괜찮으니까 가도 돼 계림아.
Your slippers.
당신의 슬리퍼.
Thank you!
감사합니다!
Are you really okay? - I am totally fine.
정말 괜찮아요? - 저는 전혀 괜찮아요.
Even if you have become the CEO, you haven't changed.
CEO가 되어도 당신은 변하지 않았습니다.
But ... what brings you here? I was so surprised to hear that you were here.
그런데... 무슨 일로 여기까지 오셨나요? 당신이 여기 있다는 말을 듣고 너무 놀랐어요.
I came to bring the laptop.
노트북을 가져오러 왔어요.
What is this? I told you I won't take it back.
이게 뭔가요? 나는 그것을 다시 가져 가지 않을 것이라고 말했습니다.
I also earn money well these days.
요즘엔 돈도 잘 벌어요.
Also, I'm already very thankful,
그리고 벌써부터 너무 감사해요
so I can't accept this as well. I also have a conscience.
그래서 나도 이 말을 받아들일 수 없다. 나에게도 양심이 있다.
What are you so thankful for?
당신은 무엇에 대해 그렇게 감사합니까?
I have my reasons.
나는 이유가 있습니다.
I'm really touched, Wung.
정말 감동받았어요, 웡.
Let's eat dinner together. I will be done in thirty minutes.
저녁을 같이 먹자. 30분 안에 끝나겠습니다.
I need to go.
난 가야 해.
- Where? - I have to go to a year-end party, so I just stopped by on the way there.
- 어디? - 송년회에 가야 해서 가는 길에 그냥 들렀어요.
I will get going.
나는 갈 것이다.
Can't I go with you?
같이 가면 안 돼요?
It's a year-end party at the publishing company.
출판사에서 열리는 송년회예요.
I know Control Z too.
나도 컨트롤 Z를 알아요.
Let's grab a meal together some other time.
나중에 같이 식사하자.
It's my treat.
내 선물이야.
- Why? - Because I'm thankful.
- 왜? - 고맙기 때문이죠.
Merry Christmas, Wung.
메리 크리스마스, 웡.
Merry Christmas. ♫ You who are so precious to me ♫
메리 크리스마스. ♫ 나에게 너무나 소중한 당신 ♫
♫ Always by my side ♫
♫ 언제나 내 곁에 ♫
♫ Remain at my side ♫
♫ 내 옆에 있어줘 ♫
That's great news.
좋은 소식이군요.
I'm having a tropical Christmas. Merry Christmas.
나는 열대 크리스마스를 보내고 있어요. 메리 크리스마스.
Even though a breakup is the end for love
비록 이별이 사랑의 끝이지만
I'm starting to realize these days that a breakup does not mean it's the end of a connection with them.
이별이 그들과의 관계의 끝을 의미하지 않는다는 것을 요즘 깨닫기 시작했습니다.
Yumi!
유미!
Congratulations!
축하해요!
♫ I only wanna be with you every day ♫
♫ 난 단지 당신과 매일 같이 있고 싶어 ♫
Congrats on completing your manuscript! Hope "My Love Muse" Season 2 is a big success. Wish you great success.
원고 완성을 축하합니다! '내사랑 뮤즈' 시즌2도 대박나길 바랍니다. 큰 성공을 기원합니다.
I'm so touched!
정말 감동받았어요!
Congratulations!
축하해요!
♫ I wonder if you felt my pounding heart ♫
♫ 내 두근거리는 심장을 당신도 느꼈을지 궁금해요 ♫
♫ Your exciting image ♫
♫ 당신의 흥미로운 이미지 ♫
Fill your glasses! Your glasses! ♫ makes me dream again ♫
안경을 채워보세요! 당신의 안경! ♫ 다시 꿈을 꾸게 해 ♫
Fill your glasses. All right!
안경을 채우세요. 괜찮은!
Our publishing company worked so hard this year! Especially our Writer Kim Yumi!
저희 출판사님 올해 너무 고생 많으셨습니다! 특히 우리 김유미 작가님!
Thank you so much.
매우 감사합니다.
To Writer Kim Yumi,
김유미 작가님께
Cheers! - Cheers!
건배! - 건배!
This year's Christmas is pretty good.
올해 크리스마스는 꽤 괜찮네요.
Even though the dating cell died.
데이트 세포가 죽었음에도 불구하고.
But still, Merry Christmas!
하지만 그래도 메리 크리스마스!
♫ I want my feelings to be wholly delivered to you ♫
♫ 내 마음이 온전히 당신에게 전해졌으면 좋겠어 ♫
♫ Awesome day if it becomes your day ♫
♫ 그것이 당신의 하루가 된다면 멋진 하루 ♫
♫ so you can always smile ♫
♫ 항상 웃을 수 있도록 ♫
♫ and clear your clouds away ♫
♫ 그리고 구름을 걷어내세요 ♫
Eonni, sleep well tonight. ♫ Everyday ♫
언니 오늘 밤 잘 자요. ♫ 매일 ♫
Get home safe!
집에 안전하게 도착하세요!
Merry Christmas, Writer-nim.
메리 크리스마스, 작가님.
Merry Christmas!
메리 크리스마스!
♫ My heart which is racing uncontrollably ♫
♫ 주체할 수 없이 뛰는 심장 ♫
♫ keeps rushing my footsteps ♫
♫ 계속 내 발걸음을 서두르고 있어요 ♫
♫ going toward you ♫
♫ 당신을 향해 가고 있어요 ♫
So pretty.
너무 예뻐요.
♫ I think of them all day if I was wrong ♫
♫ 내 생각이 틀렸다면 하루 종일 생각해요 ♫
Is it because of the alcohol?
술 때문일까요?
Strangely it's a sleepless night.
이상하게 잠이 오지 않는 밤이다.
Reason.
이유.
Who is it? Hunger, is that you?
누구입니까? 배고픔, 당신인가요?
It's me, Sensitivity.
나야, 민감성.
I suddenly wanted to sing a song.
갑자기 노래가 부르고 싶었어요.
In the middle of the night?
한밤중에?
♪ Rockabye
♪ 로커바이
- Why do you want to sing that song whenever we want to sleep? - Again? Hey, Yumi needs to sleep.
- 왜 우리가 자고 싶을 때마다 그 노래를 부르고 싶나요? - 다시? 야, 유미는 자야 해.
I don't know. I feel restless for some reason.
모르겠습니다. 왠지 불안한 느낌이 듭니다.
Why?
왜?
It's Christmas Eve.
크리스마스 이브입니다.
I want to sing then sleep.
노래하고 자고 싶어요.
All right.
괜찮은.
♪ The day starts as if being shoved
♪ 밀린 듯 하루가 시작된다
♪ I spend the day constantly acting fearless and before I know it
♪ 나는 하루 종일 두려움 없이 행동하며 어느새 나도 모르게
♪ the night arrives ♪
♪밤이 찾아온다 ♪
♪ The dark night ♪
♪어두운 밤 ♪
♪ The sadness which I've endured all day ♪
♪ 하루종일 견뎌온 슬픔 ♪
Who's there?
거기 누구 있어요?
Who are you?
누구세요?
It's me.
나야.
Who is "me"? (Also means "Who am I?")
"나"는 누구입니까? (또한 "나는 누구인가?"를 의미함)
You are Reason.
당신은 이성입니다.
I am asking that cell, not myself.
나 자신이 아니라 그 세포를 묻는 것입니다.
It's me, Love.
나야, 사랑.
Hi, guys.
안녕, 얘들아.
Love!
사랑!
When did you come back?
언제 돌아왔나요?
A few days ago.
며칠 전.
A few days ago?
며칠 전?
I don't exactly know whether it was a few days or today?
며칠인지 오늘인지 정확히는 모르겠습니다.
Because I was suddenly sucked in.
갑자기 빨려들어갔거든요.
Where am I?
나는 어디에 있습니까?
When I opened my eyes, I was back.
눈을 떴을 때 나는 돌아왔다.
I'm late because I had to walk back from the desert.
사막에서 걸어서 돌아가야 해서 늦었어요.
I couldn't fly because I'm not the prime cell.
나는 프라임 셀이 아니기 때문에 날 수 없습니다.
Anyway, it's good to see you, even though I don't know how you got back.
아무튼, 만나서 반가워요. 어떻게 돌아왔는지는 모르겠지만요.
I missed you.
나는 당신을 그리워했다.
Love!
사랑!
I missed you guys too!
나도 너희들이 보고 싶었어!
Love came back on Christmas Eve.
크리스마스 이브에 사랑이 돌아왔습니다.
She came back after a year.
그녀는 1년 만에 돌아왔다.
I'm not sure how she was able to come back.
그녀가 어떻게 돌아올 수 있었는지 잘 모르겠습니다.
Was it because of Ba Bi?
바비 때문이었을까?
Merry Christmas!
메리 크리스마스!
Or was it because of Wung?
아니면 웅 때문이었나요?
Let's go!
갑시다!
Merry is celebrating Christmas!
메리님이 크리스마스를 축하하고 있어요!
Hurry, come in.
서둘러 들어오세요.
Come in. It's fine, it's fine.
들어와요. 괜찮아요. 괜찮아요.
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Writer, these people are the next generation of our publishing company.
작가님, 이 사람들이 우리 출판사의 차세대 인재들입니다.
I brought them here to introduce you.
소개하려고 데려왔습니다.
Hello!
안녕하세요!
Nice to meet you! Nice to meet you!
만나서 반가워요! 만나서 반가워요!
When Miss Mi Yeon goes on maternity leave,
미연씨가 출산휴가를 가면
you will be working with this guy right here starting next year.
당신은 내년부터 바로 여기서 이 사람과 일하게 될 거예요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
- I said he is the one who will be responsible for you starting next year. - Uh huh. Oh!
- 내년부터 당신을 책임질 사람이 바로 그 사람이라고 했어요. - 어허. 오!
Hello!
안녕하세요!
Let's do our best, fighting!
힘내자, 화이팅!
Let's do it!
해보자!
Or was it because of another reason? ♫ The day starts ♫
아니면 다른 이유 때문이었나요? ♫ 하루가 시작됩니다 ♫
Is it Love?
사랑인가요?
Love? ♫ as if being shoved ♫
사랑? ♫ 밀쳐진 듯 ♫
- Hey! - Love!
- 여기요! - 사랑!
Love!
사랑!
You guys! ♫ I spend the day constantly ♫
여러분! ♫ 나는 하루를 끊임없이 보낸다 ♫
Whatever the reason, it's good. ♫ acting fearless ♫
이유가 무엇이든 좋습니다. ♫ 용감하게 행동함 ♫
Because Love returned
사랑이 돌아왔으니까
and Yumi was ready to be happier.
그리고 유미는 더 행복해질 준비가 되어 있었습니다.
♫ The dark night ♫
♫ 어두운 밤 ♫
♫ The sadness which I've endured all day ♫
♫ 하루종일 견뎌온 슬픔 ♫
♫ arrives like a routine ♫
♫ 일상처럼 도착해 ♫
- Wow. - Yes!
- 우와. - 예!
Here, grab my hand.
여기, 내 손을 잡아요.
Love, sit here. ♫ I hide in the middle of nowhere ♫
사랑아, 여기 앉아라. ♫ 나는 외딴 곳에 숨어 있어요 ♫
Thanks. ♫ Pathetically with a thud landing on the floor ♫
감사해요. ♫ 한심하게도 쿵 하는 소리와 함께 바닥에 착지 ♫
It's nice. ♫ I am crying ♫
좋네요. ♫ 나는 울고 있어요 ♫
Wow, it looks like cotton candy.
와, 솜사탕 같군요.
Would that taste good, too? ♫ Today, too ♫
그것도 맛있을까? ♫ 오늘도 ♫
- We can't miss - a moment like this.
- 우리는 놓칠 수 없어 - 이런 순간.
Yumi! Aren't you happy?
유미! 당신은 행복하지 않습니까?
♫ Dark feelings will be passed tonight ♫
♫ 오늘밤 어두운 감정은 지나가리라 ♫
- It's pretty. - It's really pretty.
- 예쁘네요. - 정말 예뻐요.
I want to have a snowball fight.
눈싸움을 하고 싶어요.
It's even better looking at it from up high.
높은 곳에서 보니 더욱 멋지네요.
Look at that!
저것 좀 봐!
It's really nice.
정말 좋네요.
♫ I'm going tonight to the shining place ♫
♫ 오늘밤 빛나는 곳으로 갈 거야 ♫
♫ We are going to the shining place ♫
♫ 우리는 빛나는 곳으로 갑니다 ♫
My stomach hurts.
배가 아프다.
Did I drink too much?
내가 너무 많이 마셨나?
Unknown: Writer, did you get home safely yesterday?
정체불명: 작가님, 어제 집에 무사히 도착하셨나요?
Unknown?
알려지지 않은?
Who could it be?
누구일까요?
Unknown: Writer, did you get home safely yesterday?
정체불명: 작가님, 어제 집에 무사히 도착하셨나요?
Oh, it must the publishing house employee.
아, 출판사 직원이겠죠.
I don't have his number.
그 사람 전화번호는 없어요.
Yes, I got home all right.
네, 집에 잘 도착했어요.
But I'm sorry because I drank a lot yesterday,
그런데 어제 술을 많이 마셔서 미안해
I don't really remember who you are.
나는 당신이 누구인지 잘 기억하지 못합니다.
Oh, I introduced myself to you yesterday.
아, 어제 제 소개를 했는데요.
I will be working with you starting next year when Team Leader Mi Yeon takes her maternity leave.
내년부터 미연팀장님이 출산휴가를 시작하시면서 함께 일하게 되었습니다.
Oh, that's right.
아, 그렇군요.
He did introduce himself.
그는 자신을 소개했습니다.
What was his name?
그의 이름은 무엇입니까?
My name is Sin Sun Rok.
제 이름은 신순록입니다.
Yumi Film End Scene
유미 영화 마지막 장면
Kim Go Eun as Kim Yumi
김유미 역 김고은
♫ In so many thoughts we ♫
♫ 우리는 수많은 생각 속에서 ♫
Park Jin Young as Yu Ba Bi
유바비 역 박진영
♫ Let's put behind us our weary hearts ♫
♫ 지친 마음을 뒤로합시다 ♫
♫ and think about someone ♫
♫ 그리고 누군가에 대해 생각해 보세요 ♫
Ahn Bo Hyun as Gu Wung
구웅 역 안보현
♫ I uselessly took an interest ♫
♫ 쓸데없이 관심을 가졌어 ♫
♫ In the times ♫
♫ 시대에 ♫
♫ which I always spent the same way crying ♫
♫ 나는 늘 같은 방식으로 울며 지냈지 ♫
♫ Although my fading image ♫
♫ 내 희미한 이미지에도 불구하고 ♫
♫ may seem miserable  ♫
♫ 비참해 보일 수도 있어요 ♫
Thanks to Channel Manager anna79_9
채널 관리자 anna79_9에게 감사드립니다
Thanks to Segmenters: bepina (Chief), pilar_velasquez, kitty100, dudie,
Segmenters에게 감사드립니다: bepina (Chief), pilar_velasquez, kitty100, dudie,
Thanks to Segmenters (cont/d) cgwm808, porkypine90_261, anna79_9, vcnng_365
Segmenters에게 감사드립니다(계속/d) cgwm808, pigypine90_261, anna79_9, vcnng_365
Thanks to English subtitlers: nomi637, cherae_lynn, laks_727, euib_ , keiratc, stars4u,
영어 자막 제공자에게 감사드립니다: nomi637, cherae_lynn, laks_727, euib_ , keiratc,stars4u,
English subtitlers cont/d: sophie2you, unnieshimkoong, merarijime12, dramadwarfie, allie_sun
영어 자막(계속/d): sophie2you, unnieshimkoong, merarijime12, Dramadwarfie, allie_sun
Thanks to English Editors: cgwm808 (Chief), irmar (English), nomi637 (Translation)
영어 편집자들에게 감사드립니다: cgwm808(Chief), irmar(영어), nomi637(번역)
♫ so that you won't forget me ♫
♫ 네가 나를 잊지 않도록 ♫
♫ In the season which passes ♫
♫ 지나가는 계절에 ♫
♫ in the moment which stopped wordlessly ♫
♫말 없이 멈춘 순간에 ♫
♫ perhaps while looking at each other ♫
♫ 아마도 서로를 바라보면서 ♫
♫ will we hang on? ♫
♫ 우리 좀 더 버틸까? ♫
♫ Although I am a little scared ♫
♫ 조금은 겁이 나지만 ♫
♫ of this approaching day ♫
♫ 다가오는 날의 ♫
♫ If it happens will you say to me ♫
♫ 그런 일이 생기면 나에게 말해줄래 ♫
♫ "you did well" and "good job"? ♫
♫ "잘했어" 그리고 "수고했어"? ♫